# Mustafa Akbari Software Engineer

Email: Akbarimustafa64@gmail.com

Phone: 00491795253045Birth date: 06.12.1991

• Address: Am Steinfeld 3, 85659 Forstern, Germany

### **Executive Summary**

A highly skilled IT professional with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and over 5 years of experience in IT administration, database management, and web development.

I am a collaborative team player with excellent communication skills and a knack for solving problems effectively. I am enthusiastic about joining the tech industry and eager to become part of a dynamic development team where I can both contribute and grow professionally.

Dedicated to continuous learning and currently enhancing professional skills through a Full Stack Development program at Code Institute.

# **Education**

February 2024–Present

## **Diploma in Full Stack Software Development**

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland -

(Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

#### **Technologies:**

- Frontend
  - HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap
- Backend
  - Python, Django, Flask, APIs
- Database
  - postgreSQL

December 2020-August 2022

#### **Skills Enhancement**

Udemy, Code with Mosh (online resources)

## **Technologies:**

- Python programming language
- Django framework

November 2010-December 2014

#### **Bachelor of Computer Science**

Aria University, Afg

#### **Education and Training:**

- Data structures and algorithms
- Basics of programming
- Programming languages
- Relational database design and SQL
- Software development
- Data science

## **Technical Skillset**

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python

Databases: MySQL, Postgres

Frameworks: Django, jQuery, Bootstrap, Flask

Containers: Docker

APIs: Restfull API

Operating systems: Windows, Linux

Version Control: Git, Github

## **Work Experience**

November 2022 – January 2024 Freelancer (Backend Development)

Spottech, New Zealand

- Development and implementation of backend functions for various applications.
- Leveraging modern technologies, such as Django, to seamlessly integrate API endpoints and implement database-driven functions.
- Proactively engaged in the design and development of backend systems to ensure seamless operations.
- Consistently optimize and maintain applications to uphold high standards of performance and quality.
- Effectively manage and optimize SQL databases to meet end-user requirements.

April 2018–October 2020 Database Administrator

UHCC, Afg

- Database design and creation.
- Maintain database standards and policies.
- Managing database availability and performance.
- Incident and problem management.
- Database administration for optimal use.
- Implementation of event triggers for problem detection.
- Database maintenance and optimization.
- Monitor usage and security.

March 2016–January 2018 Database Analyzer

MBC, Iran

- development of an efficient inventory management software.
- Design and administration of financial software in Microsoft Excel.
- Database maintenance to ensure integrity and accuracy of financial data.

## **IT Administrator**

TEC, Afg

- Troubleshooting network problems.
- Management of printers, copiers and fax machines.
- Server maintenance and disaster recovery.
- Monitoring of UPS workstations and operational printers.
- Backup support for workflow system.
- Ensuring password and data security in desktop environments.

# **Certifications**

- Code Institute Fullstack Web Development on going
- Code with Mosh Complate Django (16 hours)
- Udemy 100 Days of Code (54 hours)
- Python Programming Masterclass (63 hours)
- Bachelor of Computer Science

## **Interests/Additional Information**

- Fluent Persion, Fluent English, Fluent Turkish, Good German
- Fitness and wellness activities